# Paul Adams

#### Technology Leader

 $\$  +1-615-556-6507 @ paul@adams.io  $\mathscr O$  https://adams.io  $\$  Franklin, Tennessee

**SUMMARY** 

Results-oriented, goal-driven technologist with 18+ years of leadership experience in software development and IT infrastructure. Diverse background includes building and motivating teams, strategic planning, software-as-a-service (Saas) products, private equity-backed startups, growth-stage companies, various technology stacks, and consulting. Strong collaboration, analytical, and communication skills.

**EXPERIENCE** 

#### Mobile Software Engineering Manager

Quore 09/2019 - Ongoing Franklin, TN

- Leads a team of Android and iOS Engineers who provide software solutions for 33K+ monthly hospitality industry users
- Employs best practices that provide a 99.9% crash-free architecture and adherence to multiple data privacy regulations
- Promotes personal skill improvement to boost team productivity while ensuring high product quality

### Senior Mobile Software Engineer

Contractor 09/2015 - 09/2019

- Collaborated with stakeholders and cross-functional teams to devise achievable technology roadmaps for 17 product initiatives
- Applied agile software development practices throughout the lifecycle of each project, assuring consistently on-time deliverables
- Engineered 206+ *n*-tier titles among a dozen different markets
- Designed, developed, and maintained three nonprofit websites

# Information Technology Manager

U.S. Army 05/1984 - 07/2000

- Coordinated and supervised the employment, operation, management, and maintenance of information technology systems worldwide in mobile and fixed facilities
- Wrote programs to handle the collection, manipulation, and distribution of data for an array of applications and requirements
- Operated telecommunications systems, including automated networks and a full spectrum of data links and circuits

**SKILLS** 

Leadership • Agile • Analytics •

Technical Writing • Software Testing •

Offshore Resourcing • Data Privacy •

RESTful APIs • Relational Databases •

Amazon Web Services (EC2/RDS) •

Mobile & Web Development • Swift •

JavaScript • Java • Kotlin • Ruby •

Biometric Authentication • Bluetooth LE •

Machine Learning • Push Notifications •

Augmented Reality • UI/UX Design

**COURSES** 

iOS Development Course

U.S. Army Information Technology Specialist Advanced Leader Course

U.S. Army Ranger School

**EDUCATION** 

# Graduate Study, Counseling

Thomas University

# Bachelor's Degree, Psychology

Thomas University